Chenghui Zhou

https://zhouchenghui.github.io/ (+1) 412-500-3946 chenghuz@cs.cmu.edu

PROFILE

I am a graduating machine learning PhD student from Carnegie Mellon University. My thesis is on generative models and their applications to discrete structured data, such as molecules, programs, and text. During my time at CMU and industry internships, I have gained hands-on experiences with diffusion models, VAEs, GANs, transformers and RNNs in real world settings.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Machine Learning – Carnegie Mellon University

APRIL 2024 (EXPECTED)

Thesis Topic: Generative Models and Their Applications to Discrete Structured Data

Advisor: Barnabás Póczos

M.S. in Machine Learning - Carnegie Mellon University

December 2018

Related Coursework: Deep Reinforcement Learning, Probabilistic Graphical Model, Intermediate Statistics, Statistical Machine Learning, Convex Optimization

B.S. in Honours Computer Science - McGill University

May 2016

MINOR IN STATISTICS Advisor: Joelle Pineau

Industry & Research Experience

Applied Scientist Intern

May 2020 - August 2020

CodeGuru team, Amazon Web Service, Inc.

• Leveraging CodeBERT for effective code retrieval from repositories using contrastive learning

Research Intern

May 2018 - August 2018

Predictive Algorithm team, Zoll LifeVest

• Applying sequence modeling techniques for robust classification of cardiac rhythms in ECG segments

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2014 – August 2015

Reasoning and Learning Lab, McGill University

• Improving predictions for tracking in robotics by learning a predictive linear Gaussian model

Publications & Working Papers

- Chenghui Zhou, Kaushal Gumpula, Barnabás Póczos Generating Molecules in 3D at Equilibrium with Equivariant Diffusion Model In Progress
- Chenghui Zhou, Barnabás Póczos Objective-Agnostic Enhancement of Molecule Properties via Multi-Stage VAE Submitted to International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2024
- Chenghui Zhou, Barnabás Póczos Improving Molecule Properties Through 2-Stage VAE Machine Learning for Structural Biology Workshop, NeurIPS, 2022.
- Chenghui Zhou*, Frederic Koehler*, Viraj Mehta*, Andrej Risteski Variational Autoencoders in the Presence of Low-Dimensional Data: Landscape and Implicit Bias International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.
- Chenghui Zhou, Chun-Liang Li, Barnabás Póczos Unsupervised Program Synthesis for Images by Sampling without Replacement Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2021.

- Chenghui Zhou, Chun-Liang Li, Barnabás Póczos Unsupervised Program Synthesis for Images Using Tree-Structured LSTM Deep Reinforcement Learning Workshop & Learning with Rich Experience Workshop (one of two selected oral presentations) NeurIPS, 2019.
- Robin Schmucker, Chenghui Zhou, Manuela Veloso
 Multimodal Movement Activity Recognition Using a Robot's Proprioceptive Sensors
 RoboCup Symposium, 2018.
- Chenghui Zhou, Manuela Veloso Interception in Continuous Space Using Deep Reinforcement Learning Submitted to International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2018.
- Michiel de Jong, Kevin Zhang, Travers Rhodes, Aaron Roth, Robin Schmucker, Chenghui Zhou, Sofia Ferreira, João Cartucho, Manuela Veloso Towards a Robust Interactive and Learning Social Robot International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2018.
- Chenghui Zhou, Borja Balle, Joelle Pineau Learning Time Series Models for Pedestrian Motion Prediction International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2016.

TEACHING

2021	Teaching assistant for Convex Optimization (Carnegie Mellon University)
2018	Teaching assistant for Statistical Machine Learning (Carnegie Mellon University)
2016	Teaching assistant for Introduction to Software Systems (McGill University)
2015	Teaching assistant for Foundations of Programming (McGill University)

COMMUNITY SERVICE

2022 - Now	Served as a mentor in the PhD Peers Program of Machine Learning Department
2019	Served on the Retreat Committee of Machine Learning Department
2018 - 2020	Served as SCS4ALL Representative for Machine Learning Department

LANGUAGES

Computer Skills

9 9	Python, Java, C, Matlab, LATEX	English	Fluent
Operating systems	Linux, Windows, OS X	Chinese	Fluent
ML packages	PyTorch, Keras, JAX, Tensorflow, Sklearn	French	Elementary
Chemistry packages	RDKit, OpenBabel, OpenMM		

SCHOLARSHIPS & AWARDS

2013 - 2016	Dean's Honours List – McGill University Faculty of Science
2015	Science Undergraduate Research Award – McGill University
2015	Emily Ross Crawford Scholarship – McGill University
2014	Scholarship for BSc Computer Science Honours Student – Le Réseau ACTION TI
2013	Faculty of Science Scholarship - McGill University